MUHAMMAD MEHDI RAJANI

mehdi.nedian@gmail.com (+92) 334 - 3450462

A technical resource with knowledge of JavaScript and Experience with Javascript based libraries/frameworks like (Angular, React Js, React native and Vue Js). In other words, I am hands-on with Mobile and Web Application using Javascript. It's around 4+ years plus experience contributing as a Front-end engineer in the IT industry.

Relevant Work Experience

13 Oct 2021 -Present

Senior Software Engineer

Senior Software Engineer - Securiti.ai

- Vue Is
 - Started working on Vue js
 - Architectural work using Vue
- Nest JS (Worked Nest Js as a backend tool.)
- Team Management (Managing team along with knowledge sharing with entire team)
- CSS (Flexbox, Bootstrap, Angular Material, Vuetify)

July 2018 -10 Oct 2021

Software Engineer

Software Engineer - IOMECHS

- Angular 2+
 - Worked on Angular 2+
 - Experience with NGRX or NGSX
 - Write Unit test using Jasmine + Karma
 - Write E2E testing using Protractor
 - o Managing performance factors in Angular Application

Firebase

- o Manage realtime Db
- o Realtime chat App using Firebase
- o Realtime Notification using Firebase
- Cloud functions in Firebase

React

- o Can work on class component along with functional component approach
- Worked on Redux like (Thunk)
- Use Most library to handle Reactivity with Redux
- React Native (Android and IOS)
 - o Realtime chat using Firebase.
 - o Notifications in app.
 - Somehow calling features.

Jan 2015 - Aug 2016

Associate Software Engineer(Internship program)

Associate Software Engineer - Koderlabs

- Angular.js (Small Social Media).
- JQuery.
- Laravel (Back end)
- Wordpress

Education

2014 - 2018 Bachelor's in Computer Science and IT (BCS)

NED UNIVERSITY OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY.

2012-2014 Intermediate (Computer Science)

NCR-CET COLLEGE.

2002-2012 Matriculation (Computer Science)

Al- Murtaza School.

Additional Skills

- Like to contribute to open-source like Technical sessions / Host a session.
- Like to work in a team / Lead a team etc.
- Sports (Cricket).

Contributions & Sample Project

1) GITHUB CONTRIBUTIONS

https://github.com/mehdirajani5
https://github.com/mmehdirajani05/

2) STACK OVERFLOW CONTRIBUTIONS

https://stackoverflow.com/users/6413487/mehdi-rajani

3) Technical Talks Slides

https://slides.com/muhammad-mehdi-rajani/